<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>This American Archive</title>
    <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org</link>
    <description>Autogenerated feed of the This American Life archive.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © Ira Glass / This American Life</copyright>
    <itunes:image href="https://i.imgur.com/0MMrLC4.png"/>

    <item>
      <title>871: The Thing About Things (Promo)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/871/the-thing-about-things</link>
      <itunes:episode>871</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Three stories about the strange power inanimate objects can hold over us.

Prologue
Nunzio gets caught in a kind of servile relationship…with a scooter. (8 minutes)

Act One: A Rock and a Hard Place
Ted was six when he first picked up a rock from the Petrified Forest National Park. Nearly 50 years later, he really wishes he hadn’t. Aviva DeKornfeld talked to him. (15 minutes)

Act Two: A Few Hundred of My Favorite Things
Heavyweight host Jonathan Goldstein leaps in to help a family, who are not entirely sure they want or need his help, get rid of their stuff. (31 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/promos/871.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>844: This Is the Case of Henry Dee</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/844/this-is-the-case-of-henry-dee</link>
      <itunes:episode>844</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Thirteen parole board members decide whether or not one man should be released from prison.

Prologue
Henry Dee has been locked up for most of his life, nearly 50 years. Now, he’s up for parole. Reporter Ben Austen tells the story. (19 minutes)

Part 1: Part 1
The parole board members puzzle through the pros and cons of releasing Henry Dee from prison and cast their votes. (26 minutes)

Part 2: Part 2
Reporter Ben Austen continues the story. (8 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://dcs-spotify.megaphone.fm/NPR6325401197.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>870: My Other Self</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/870/my-other-self</link>
      <itunes:episode>870</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>What happens when people create alternate versions of themselves and release them into the wild?

Prologue
Host Ira Glass talks about a recent experience being interviewed and the realization that he was being asked about another version of himself. (4 minutes)

Act One: Me and My Shadow
Reporter Evan Ratliff creates an AI version of himself and then sets it loose on the world. This story was adapted from Evan's podcast, Shell Game. (43 minutes)

Act Two: Papa Was a Trolling Stone
Emmanuel Dzotsi explores the phenomenon of people lying on first dates to project a better version of themselves. Plus, he gets into a very personal example from his own life. (8 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://dcs-spotify.megaphone.fm/NPR9417124313.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>869: Harold</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/869/harold</link>
      <itunes:episode>869</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>The story of Harold Washington and the white backlash that ensued when he became Chicago's first Black mayor.

Prologue
As New York City’s Democratic establishment attempts to resist the candidacy of Zohran Mamdani, we look back at another mayoral candidate who upset the established political machine. (7 minutes)

Act One: Yesterday
A history of the brief mayoral career of Harold Washington and its lessons for Black and white America, as told by people close to him. (39 minutes)

Act Two: The Present and the Future
Ira revisits interviews with Chicago voters from the 1997 and 2007 rebroadcasts of this episode. In 1997, ten years after Harold Washington’s death, not much had changed in Chicago. By 2007, attitudes had begun to shift slowly, and another Black politician from Chicago was on the rise — Barack Obama. Ira also speaks to David Axelrod, an advisor to both Harold Washington and Barack Obama. (10 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://dcs-spotify.megaphone.fm/NPR8814052881.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>868: The Hand That Rocks The Gavel (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/868/the-hand-that-rocks-the-gavel</link>
      <itunes:episode>868</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>A group of immigration judges, who almost never speak to the press, describes the dismantling of our immigration court system from the inside.

Prologue
Zoe Chace gives an eyewitness account of what has been happening at 26 Federal Plaza, an immigration courthouse in New York City. (5 minutes)

Act One: Act One
The judges walk us through how different their jobs have become in just the past few months, because of sweeping policy changes by Trump’s Department of Justice. (26 minutes)

Act Two: Act Two
It gets extremely personal for the judges. Also, the story of one person who got pushed through the new immigration court system this summer. (23 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/868.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>867: College Disorientation (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/867/college-disorientation</link>
      <itunes:episode>867</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Things are different on college campuses this year. We see inside the drama, with students and staff.

Prologue
We go to orientation at Arizona State University and meet international students who are trying to make friends. (6 minutes)

Act One: My Black President
The president of the Black Student Union at the University of Utah fights to keep the B in BSU. (30 minutes)

Act Two: The Art of the Deal
A definition of antisemitism, canceled classes, and angry professors at Columbia University. (16 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/867.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>866: Watch Out for That Tree</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/866/watch-out-for-that-tree</link>
      <itunes:episode>866</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Small human plans that run into much larger obstacles.

Prologue
Angela's dad, an accountant, made a spreadsheet to prepare for their family trip to a national park. But there are things you never think to put in a spreadsheet. (7 minutes)

Act One: Forces Outside Our Control
A young couple, excited to start a new chapter in their lives, is suddenly put on a very different trajectory. (30 minutes)

Act Two: The Engineer
A sixteen-year-old plans out a prank, and a complete stranger from Honduras ends up in a million-dollar deal. What could go wrong? (25 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://dcs-spotify.megaphone.fm/NPR5310093493.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>865: The Other Territory (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/865/the-other-territory</link>
      <itunes:episode>865</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Since October 7, Israel has intensified restrictions on West Bank Palestinians while global attention focused on Gaza. We travel to the West Bank to see these changes in person.

Prologue
Ira joins Hamed on his Monday commute. He has to navigate a constantly changing series of checkpoints and roadblocks to get to work each day. Hamed works for Comet-ME, which sets up solar panels, water systems, and security cameras in small villages all over the West Bank. (13 minutes)

Act One: Ali and the Duster
Settler violence has worsened significantly in the West Bank since October 7, 2023. Yael Even Or travels to a tiny village called Tuba, surrounded by Israeli settlements, to meet the 27-year-old resident trying to protect it. (26 minutes)

Snapshots (podcast only)
Two quick snapshots of life in the West Bank since October 7th. (6 minutes)

Act Two: What Happened to Walid
After October 7th, Israeli Minister of Security Itamar Ben-Gvir increased restrictions on Palestinian prisoners in Israeli security prisons. Prisoners started dying. Dana Chivvis looks into one of those deaths. (25 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/865.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>864: Chicago Hope (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/864/chicago-hope</link>
      <itunes:episode>864</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>The story of the most commonly performed surgery, and what goes terribly wrong with it.

Prologue
Ira Glass introduces the first episode of an inventive new podcast from longtime This American Life producer and editor Susan Burton.

Act One: Act One
Susan Burton introduces Mindy, a labor and delivery nurse at UI Health at the University of Illinois at Chicago. (5 minutes)

Act Two: Act Two
Another labor and delivery nurse at UI Health, Clara, gets ready to deliver twins at her own hospital and receives an epidural. (19 minutes)

Act Three: Act Three
Clara’s anesthesia is not working. She is now in the middle of major abdominal surgery, and she can feel that surgery. (21 minutes)

Act Four: Act Four
Heather, the head of obstetric anesthesia at UI Health, gets up onstage and asks a ballroom full of hundreds of anesthesiologists to wrestle with the question of why patients are feeling pain during C-sections, and what they can do to solve it. (8 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/864.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>863: Championship Window (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/863/championship-window</link>
      <itunes:episode>863</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>People on a mission to achieve their goals before their window of opportunity closes.

Prologue
Guest host Emmanuel Dzotsi goes to a packed sports bar in Brooklyn for his favorite soccer team’s biggest game in years. (6 minutes)

Act One: Pregnant, Pause
Connie Wang tells the story of a championship window she didn't realize she was in — until it was too late. (14 minutes)

Act Two: Cry Hard with a Vengeance
Seth Lind, our Operations Director, isn’t a crier. But he wants to connect with his emotions, so guest host Emmanuel Dzotsi sets up an unconventional experiment. (14 minutes)

Act Three: Benched Expectations
Two college baseball teams with horrible losing streaks — a combined 141 games — are scheduled to play each other. One of them must finally win. (14 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/863.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>862: Some Things We Don't Do Anymore</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/862/some-things-we-dont-do-anymore</link>
      <itunes:episode>862</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Trump froze U.S. foreign aid and dismantled USAID. We examine the agency’s impact and hear from people trying to navigate this chaotic moment.

Prologue
Just one box of a specially enriched peanut butter paste can save the life of a severely malnourished child. So why have 500,000 of those boxes been stuck in warehouses in Rhode Island? (13 minutes)

Act One: 63 Years, 7 Months, 26 Days
USAID was founded in 1961. Since then, it has spent hundreds of billions of dollars all over the world. What did that get us? Producer David Kestenbaum talked with Joshua Craze and John Norris about that. (12 minutes)

Act Two: Case Study
Two Americans moved to Eswatini when that country was the epicenter of the AIDS epidemic. With support from USAID, they built a clinic and started serving HIV+ patients. Now that US support for their clinic has ended, they are wondering if what they did was entirely a good thing. (27 minutes)

Act Three: Two Daughters
When USAID suddenly stopped all foreign assistance without warning or a transition plan, it sent people all over the world scrambling. Especially those relying on daily medicine provided by USAID. Producer Ike Sriskandarajah spoke to two families in Kenya who were trying to figure it out. (8 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/862/7S3DAAmXKxlrwLydU4ktF23n-gISlUKO-sOG7xCSrSA/862.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>861: Group Chat (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/861/group-chat</link>
      <itunes:episode>861</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Conversations across a divide: People who are outside a war zone check in with family, friends, and strangers inside.

Prologue
The Hammash family’s group chat unfolds over texts, starting before the war. (8 minutes)

Act One: I’m Fine, Don’t Worry
When Yousef Hammash left Gaza a year ago, his sisters decided to stay behind. We hear about the toll that separation has taken on Yousef and the sister he’s closest to, Aseel. (30 minutes)

Act Two: Week Eleven
Mohammed Mhawish, a reporter who left Gaza a year ago with his family, talks to a young woman in Gaza about how she manages her hunger. Israel blockaded all food from Gaza for more than two months. (15 minutes)

Coda: Banias
Chana gives a short update about Banias, a 9-year-old girl in Gaza she's been speaking with for months. (4 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/861.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>860: Suddenly: A Mirror! (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/860/suddenly-a-mirror</link>
      <itunes:episode>860</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>A show about people who are suddenly confronted with who they are.

Prologue
Guest host Aviva DeKornfeld tells Ira Glass about breaking into a community pool as a kid, and the split-second decision that has haunted her ever since. (4 minutes)

Act One: On Top of Spaghetti, All Covered in Shame
Some people are great in a crisis. Others, not so much. Does that mean anything about who we really are? Tobin Low investigates. (10 minutes)

Act Two: BWE: Big Wig Energy
Aviva DeKornfeld has the story of Leisha Hailey, who was certain she had the next million-dollar idea. (11 minutes)

Act Three: There Will Be Questions
Comedian Mike Birbiglia talks about the questions his daughter asks him and how trying to answer them showed him surprising reflections of himself.  (15 minutes)

Act Four: Trouble Afoot
David Kestenbaum tells the story of the suspicious disappearance of multiple shoes and a woman determined to explain it. (8 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/860.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>859: Chaos Graph</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/859/chaos-graph</link>
      <itunes:episode>859</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>People immersed in chaos try to solve for what it all adds up to.

Prologue
A scientist who is used to organizing data starts tracking scientific meetings that seem to exist only on paper—meetings that might decide the fate of years of research. The NIH website shows one reality; the empty conference rooms tell another story. She graphs the chaos. (9 minutes)

Act One: Solving For Why
American doctors returning from Gaza compare notes and start to see a pattern. (28 minutes)

Act Two: Solving For Where
A woman watches her partner get taken in handcuffs with no explanation. Days later, she spots him in the most unexpected place. The coordinates of her life suddenly don't make sense as she navigates the bewildering map of the US immigration system. (23 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/859/A0LQCKi6hd0vJ1Tf_jzyhhE0_jNAq4WotPUUd6ZToDI/859.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>858: How to Tell a Dumb American Story (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/858/how-to-tell-a-dumb-american-story</link>
      <itunes:episode>858</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>A couple devises a strategy to get their daughter's killer prosecuted and to get attention for other Native families.

Prologue
Mika Westwolf was killed in a hit-and-run on a Montana highway. Her parents thought the driver might get away with it. The driver was white. Mika was a citizen of the Blackfeet Nation. (1 minute)

Act One: Act One
Mika’s parents, Carissa Heavy Runner and Kevin Howard, share recordings of their interactions with law enforcement. (8 minutes)

Act Two: Act Two
Carissa and Kevin take matters into their own hands. (20 minutes)

Act Three: Act Three
The county prosecutor explains why he let Mika’s killer out of jail. Will Carissa and Kevin's efforts pay off? Sierra follows them to court. (33 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/858.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>857: Museum of Now</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/857/museum-of-now</link>
      <itunes:episode>857</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Artifacts and exhibits of this particular moment we are living through.

Exhibit One: Exhibit One
Ira talks to producer Emmanuel Dzotsi, who brings the first exhibit into the studio with him: a chunk of concrete with some yellow paint on it. He got it from the demolition site in Washington, DC, where the giant Black Lives Matter letters are being dug out of the street with heavy equipment. (8 minutes)

Exhibit Two: Exhibit Two
Producer Aviva DeKornfeld talks to Ranjani Srinivasan, who tells the story of how her life was transformed over five days via a series of events that started out confusing and escalated to frightening. (25 minutes)

Exhibit Three: Exhibit Three
Producer Laura Starecheski takes us inside one dramatic court hearing on the Trump administration’s executive order and new policy banning transgender people from serving in the military. (20 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/857/9MGp6qkBo_x6Hx2Cf7wX4Mli96qSsdUQFXPlQorQJ8g/857.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>856: You’ve Come to the Right Person (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/856/youve-come-to-the-right-person</link>
      <itunes:episode>856</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Sometimes, life’s biggest mysteries require one very specific person to answer them.

Prologue
7-year-old Miles has lots of questions. More specifically, he has questions about the famous car chase from “The Blues Brothers” movie. We arrange for him to talk to stunt coordinator Gary Powell so he can get the answers he so desperately wants. (9 minutes)

Act One: Ask Daniel
Producer Aviva DeKornfeld looks into why comedian Daniel Sloss’s comedy special has been responsible for so many couples breaking up. (17 minutes)

Act Two: Ask Kwaneta
We hear from Kwaneta Harris, a former nurse incarcerated in Texas, who is constantly asked for medical advice by her neighbors. (17 minutes)

Act Three: Ask Harriotte
Producer Diane Wu talks to Juna, a young woman who is getting advice from someone uniquely equipped to guide her to the love life she wants. (12 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/856.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>855: That’s a Weird Thing to Lie About (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/855/thats-a-weird-thing-to-lie-about</link>
      <itunes:episode>855</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Unnecessary and outrageous lies that make you wonder — why lie about that in the first place?

Prologue
Kasey, a woman who prides herself on her truthfulness, tries to help host Ira Glass figure out how to stop lying about one specific thing. (10 minutes)

Act One: The Real L Word
Producer Dana Chivvis talks to reporter Liz Flock about a strange experience she had in 2011. (21 minutes)

Act Two: Bully Pulpit
Host Ira Glass talks with M. Gessen about a lie they've been seeing out in the world a lot recently — the “bully lie.” (15 minutes)

Act Three: In Defense of Unnecessary Lies
We find someone brave enough to stand up and make a case FOR lying. That person is producer Ike Sriskandarajah. (8 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/855.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>854: Ten Things I Don't Want to Hate About You (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/854/ten-things-i-dont-want-to-hate-about-you</link>
      <itunes:episode>854</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Zach Mack and his dad try to mend a rift between them in a very unusual way.

Prologue
Ira Glass introduces Zach Mack’s story. (1 minute)

Part One: Part One
Zach and his father enter into an agreement that could change their entire relationship. (9 minutes)

Part Two: Part Two
Zach’s mother and sister weigh in on the agreement. (28 minutes)

Part Three: Part Three
With the year coming to an end, someone is going to have to say, “You were right, and I was wrong.” Will it change anything? (16 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/854.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>853: Groundhog Day</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/853/groundhog-day</link>
      <itunes:episode>853</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>People stuck in a loop, trying to find their way out.

Prologue
Host Ira Glass talks to B.A. Parker about her birthday tradition. (6 minutes)

Act One: Will You Still Slug Me Tomorrow?
Producer Aviva DeKornfeld speaks with a father and daughter who have been playing the same game for 25 years. (9 minutes)

Act Two: I’ll Repeat the Question
Talia Augustidis asks a single question over and over. (5 minutes)

Act Three: Raiders of the Lost Chard
Editor David Kestenbaum speaks with Jeff Permar, who is trapped in a Groundhog Day situation — with an actual groundhog! (9 minutes)

Act Four: Heart of Parkness
Parking in a big city can be a real pain. Producer Valerie Kipnis speaks with a man who has taken it upon himself to try to mitigate the weekly hassle. (14 minutes)

Act Five: It's Been a Hard Year's Night, and I've Been Working Like a Hog
Short fiction from Bess Kalb about a groundhog named Susan, who has her own opinions about the holiday named after her species. (7 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/853/vj-773LU7sVbnMJn3t-6E5Ck7umfWzuOk_odpG4gFDE/853.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>852: Pivot Point (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/852/pivot-point</link>
      <itunes:episode>852</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>People living in that in-between moment before everything changes.

Prologue
Kirk Johnson tells Ira about a strange choice he made during his family’s evacuation from the Sunset Fire in Los Angeles. (5 minutes)

Act One: Who’s Laughing Now?
Editor Nancy Updike tries to make sense of this current moment by talking to a master of dark comedy, Armando Ianucci. (19 minutes)

Act Two: The View From the Dugout
As President Trump prepares to return to the Oval Office, producer Valerie Kipnis talks to Ukrainian soldiers on the front line who wonder about what his administration could mean for them. (14 minutes)

Act Three: Period Piece
Editor Susan Burton reflects on the ramp-up to an era that comes for so many of us. (9 minutes)

Act Four: Since You’ve Been Gone
In the wake of the Eaton Fire in Altadena, California, producer Miki Meek talks to a woman on a very particular mission. (6 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/852.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>851: Try a Little Tenderness</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/851/try-a-little-tenderness</link>
      <itunes:episode>851</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>People try a radical approach to solving their problems.

Prologue
Ira meets two sisters who got into a fight, and then learned a lesson in turning the other cheek. (8 minutes)

Act One: The Big Nap
A hardened PI works the toughest case of his very young life. (18 minutes)

Act Two: The Gladiator Starring Ruffled Crow
Producer Aviva DeKornfeld talks to a man who finds himself the target of vengeful crows. (8 minutes)

Act Three: You’ll Spank Me Later For This
Comedian Josh Johnson wonders if some people should’ve been spanked as kids. (10 minutes)

Act Four: The Feels on the Bus
Writer Etgar Keret reads his story about a bus driver who refuses to open the doors for late passengers. (9 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/851/IJgReGTNzRi_o-skNRwZZee4vWzmx9SXXH3Rg5msDNs/851.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>850: If You Want to Destroy My Sweater, Hold This Thread as I Walk Away (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/850/my-sweater</link>
      <itunes:episode>850</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>The tiny thing that unravels your world.

Prologue
Ira talks to Chris Benderev, whose high school years were completely upended by an impromptu thing his teacher said. (8 minutes)

Act One: The World Has Turned and Left Me Here
For Producer Lilly Sullivan, there’s one story about her parents that defines how she sees them, their family, and their history. She finds out it might be wrong. (27 minutes)

Act Two: What’s With These Homies Dissing My Girl?
For years, Mike Comite has replayed in his head the moment when he and his bandmate blew their shot of making it as musicians. He sets out to uncover how it all went awry. (13 minutes)

Act Three: And If You See Her, Tell Her It’s Over Now
Six million Syrians fled the country after the start of its civil war. A few weeks ago, one woman watched from afar as everything in her home country changed forever – again. (9 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/850.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>849: The Narrator</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/849/the-narrator</link>
      <itunes:episode>849</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Banias is an 8-year-old kid living in Gaza. And she has a story to tell — many stories, in fact.

Prologue
While on the phone with reporter Maram Hamaid in Gaza, producer Chana Joffe-Walt gets interrupted by Maram’s daughter––Banias, eight, who grabs the phone from her mother and starts telling us about her life. The narrator arrives. (8 minutes)

Part One: Part One
Banias, an 8-year-old in Gaza, tells us about her life––her friends, the games she plays, the things she cares about. Everything but the war going on around her. (25 minutes)

Part Two: Part Two
Banias talks about the war. (20 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/849/ABhEfcY8BfdI4lL_lvyzqC-P2v25Zlt1TiMsKNwkLWk/849.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>848: The Official Unofficial Record</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/848/the-official-unofficial-record</link>
      <itunes:episode>848</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>How do you count almost 12 million votes if you’re not the government?

Prologue
Host Ira Glass sets us up for Nancy Updike’s insider account of the recent presidential election in Venezuela. The story is an incredible national drama that plays out in thousands of polling stations across the country, with regular people trying to ensure a fair vote count that everyone can agree on. (2 minutes)

Act One: Best Acta in a Dramatic Role
Producer Nancy Updike tells the story of the people of Venezuela trying to prove who won their recent presidential election beyond a shadow of a doubt. (22 minutes)

Act Two: Meanwhile, In America
Host Ira Glass spent America’s presidential election in the swing state of Michigan, where he found very little dispute over the ballot count from Republican poll challengers in Detroit now that they are doing the counting themselves. (8 minutes)

Act Three: Oh What a Hangled Web We Weave
This story is about a creepy and dangerous creature that does all kinds of terrible things. It’s also about someone trying to set the record straight on those exact assumptions about this notorious creature. (9 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/848/vsZXjD6t7LeEhQF8BU4jGTEV-QzXomundcHNRfEhdfI/848.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>847: The Truly Incredible Story of Keiko the Killer Whale</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/847/the-truly-incredible-story-of-keiko-the-killer-whale</link>
      <itunes:episode>847</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>A colossal effort to un-tame a whale and send him back to the ocean.

Prologue
Ira introduces a new series from Serial Productions and The New York Times. "The Good Whale" is about the killer whale Keiko and is reported by Daniel Alarcón. (2 minutes)

Act One: Keiko
Daniel Alarcón takes us back to the early 90’s when Keiko lived in an adventure park in Mexico City, swimming with human friends. (43 minutes)

Act Two: America’s Next Top Gobble
Producer Diane Wu travels to Minnesota, where the turkey set to be pardoned by The President of the United States later this month is having the turkiness trained out of him. (10 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/847/8cX9EreCWKDWEXovWnaVs1LUqr5XxdB3Yk5GP4PxcJ0/847.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>846: This Is the Cake We Baked (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/846/this-is-the-cake-we-baked</link>
      <itunes:episode>846</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>We talk to people who helped make Trump's victory happen and some who are looking to what’s next.

Prologue
Ira talks with Zoe Chace about watching Trump’s victory from an ecstatic room in Michigan. Then he checks in with a DC cop who was injured at the Capitol on January 6. (7 minutes)

Act One: The Largest Deportation Operation in American History
Trump has claimed that he will be able to deport between 15 and 20 million people. But neither he nor his team have spelled out exactly how they’d do it. Producer Nadia Reiman looked into what mass deportation could actually look like on the ground if and when it comes to pass. (17 minutes)

Act Two: Nobody Loves Our Latino Community and our Puerto Rican Community More Than I Do
Trump won record numbers of Latino voters this year. Ike Sriskandarajah spent the day with a guy in Pennsylvania who's been working to bring Latino voters to Trump for years. (15 minutes)

Act Three: Sometimes Revenge Can Be Justified
Ira talks with two of Trump’s “political enemies” about their post-election plans. (8 minutes)

Act Four: I’ve Done an Unbelievable Job on the Abortion Question
Ten different states had abortion rights measures on their ballots this election. Producer Miki Meek got curious about a particular kind of political ad that aired in many of those states and called up a few of the women whose stories were featured in them. (9 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/846.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>845: A Small Thing That Gives Me a Tiny Shred of Hope  (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/845/a-small-thing</link>
      <itunes:episode>845</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>A wee flame, flickering in the dark.

Prologue
Who’s trying to bridge the gap between Blue America and Red America? Ira gets a glimpse of one guy who might be able to do just that. (3 minutes)

Act One: A Tiny Thing That Gives Me Hope
A politically divided couple searches for a news source they both can trust. (26 minutes)

Act Two: Till Death Do Us Partisan
"June" is making a tactical decision about her vote this election. (13 minutes)

Act Three: Let Me Be Frank
Frank Filocomo thinks people care too much about politics when it comes to dating. His dates don’t necessarily agree. (10 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/845.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>844: This Is the Case of Henry Dee</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/844/this-is-the-case-of-henry-dee</link>
      <itunes:episode>844</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Thirteen parole board members decide whether or not one man should be released from prison.

Prologue
Henry Dee has been locked up for most of his life, nearly 50 years. Now, he’s up for parole. Reporter Ben Austen tells the story. (19 minutes)

Part 1: Part 1
The parole board members puzzle through the pros and cons of releasing Henry Dee from prison and cast their votes. (26 minutes)

Part 2: Part 2
Reporter Ben Austen continues the story. (8 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://dcs-spotify.megaphone.fm/NPR6325401197.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>843: A Little Bit of Power (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/843/a-little-bit-of-power</link>
      <itunes:episode>843</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Abbas Alawieh, a leader in the Uncommitted movement, grapples with how to get his voters the thing they want.

Prologue
When you have some power, but not a lot, how do you wield it when you’re suddenly cast into the spotlight? (4 minutes)

Act One: The Convention
Zoe Chace and Ben Terris follow Abbas Alawieh as he fights to broker a deal at the DNC – a way to potentially satisfy the people who voted “Uncommitted” in the primaries as a protest vote against Biden’s handling of the war in Israel and Gaza. (33 minutes)

Act Two: Back Home in Michigan
Three weeks after the Democratic National Convention, Abbas speaks at a tense community meeting in Michigan about the Uncommitted organizers’ general election recommendation and hears back from voters on how they feel about the Democratic nominee at this point. (15 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/843.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>842: 51 Days</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/842/51-days</link>
      <itunes:episode>842</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Chen Almog-Goldstein tells the story of life as a hostage in Gaza.

Prologue
The 251 hostages taken by Hamas a year ago have become a divisive symbol in Israel. Host Ira Glass talks about the father of one hostage, and what happened to him at a protest last week when he called for a hostage deal. (6 minutes)

Part One: The Abduction
On this week’s show, we’re airing excerpts of interviews with former hostages produced by an Israeli podcast, Echad Bayom. In these interviews they describe, in a remarkably detailed and complicated way, what happened to them a year ago.

Part Two: Daily Life in Captivity
Chen’s story continues, with a description of what it was like to be hidden in a small apartment with her children and their captors. (6 minutes)

Part Three: The Guards
Chen talks about the complicated relationship between her family and the people holding them hostage. (6 minutes)

Part Four: News from Home
Chen describes hearing the Israeli news while in captivity, including one night when her own father was interviewed. (4 minutes)

Part Five: Moving Around
Chen talks about what it was like to walk around the streets of Gaza in disguise and their eventual release, 51 days after they were taken from their home. (13 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/842/OjBP9MAE4QRwCDZTRic5kMUeSQHtv2NXyrfBNYTxDPM/842.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>841: My Senior Year</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/841/my-senior-year</link>
      <itunes:episode>841</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>One kid comes to America as an exchange student and commits herself to the senior year experience.

Prologue
We talk to high school seniors in Salt Lake City who are trying to have the perfect year. (5 minutes)

Act One: Yes 2024
Every year, thousands of teenagers come from all over the world to experience American high school. Last year, thirteen students from Palestine came to the US on a program sponsored by the US State Department. We tell the story of a girl named Majd, from Gaza, and her extraordinary year in America. (50 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/841/jR4a6c5E4vgDWxrwf3AIEROmPQcc7tXm19AGWks40zA/841.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>840: How Are You Not Seeing This? (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/840/how-are-you-not-seeing-this</link>
      <itunes:episode>840</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>People trying and struggling to see what another person sees.

Prologue
Guest-host Tobin Low talks to comedian Tig Notaro about a jarring ride to school with her son. (6 minutes)

Act One: There Will Be Blood
Producer Aviva DeKornfeld heads to the Calgary Stampede to watch as men try out a machine designed to simulate menstrual cramps. (15 minutes)

Act Two: Face Your Demons
A man can’t seem to see anyone in his life for who they really are, plunging his life into chaos. (18 minutes)

Act Three: Pump It Up
Senior Editor David Kestenbaum hears about a way to save some money and help save the world. All he needs is a little help. (5 minutes)

Act Four: I’m Great, Thanks For NOT Asking
Marie Phillips reads a short story involving an aloof friend, a goose, and some extreme gardening. (7 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/840.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>839: Meet Me at the Fair (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/839/meet-me-at-the-fair</link>
      <itunes:episode>839</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>We spend a few days at the Iowa State Fair.

Prologue
A big bull, a giant slide, and cowboys on horseback shooting balloons are just a few sights you can take in at the Iowa State Fair. Some people come for the spectacle, and some are the spectacle. (8 minutes)

Act One: Carny Confidential
Bailey Leavitt comes from a family of carnies. For her, one of the most thrilling things she looks for at the fair is someone who is really good at luring people into spending money at their stand. She takes Ira on an insider’s search for “an agent.” (16 minutes)

Grandstand Chicken (Podcast Only)
Motley Crue pledged never to play the fairgrounds. Then they did. We wondered what that had been like for them. They agreed to an interview, but then they flinched. (1 minute)

Act Two: How Bad is Your Bunny?
What life lessons can kids learn at the 4-H rabbit competition? A lot. (11 minutes)

Act Three: Limp Biscuit
The Iowa State Fair awarded coveted slots to just nine new food vendors this year. All of them are run by people who already own restaurants or who’ve done other big fairs. All except for an unlikely newcomer: Biscuit Bar. (19 minutes)

Act Four: Last Stand (Podcast Only)
As the ferris wheel goes dark and the fair is closing down, one game is racing to meet their quota. Ira watches until the end. (3 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/839.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>838: Letters! Actual Letters! (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/838/letters-actual-letters</link>
      <itunes:episode>838</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>When the best—and perhaps only—way to say something is to write it down.

Prologue
Ira goes out with a letter carrier, ‘Grace,’ as she delivers mail on her route. He learns about the people who bring us our mail and also how people treat their mail. (11 minutes)

Act One: Dear Alice
Writing a letter decades after an event that shaped her life was the only way that Nicole Piasecki could make some sense of it. (18 minutes)

Act Two: Dear Miss
Yorkshire, 1866. A farmer overcomes his timidity and writes a very important letter to a local beauty. (3 minutes)

Act Three: Dear Dr. Kestenbaum
When senior editor David Kestenbaum was still a rookie reporter, he wrote an email to a legend. Then he waited...and waited...for a reply. (6 minutes)

Act Four: Dear US Army
A woman writes an unusual letter on behalf of her husband. (1 minute)

Act Five: Dear Zoe
Producer Zoe Chace compares the letters a person gets and the letters they wish they got. (12 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/838.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>837: Swim Towards the Shark (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/837/swim-towards-the-shark</link>
      <itunes:episode>837</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>In a crisis, when all logic suggests that you get away from the dangerous thing, how will you respond?

Prologue
Ira talks to two members of a recreational swimming club who intentionally swam straight toward a shark that had just bitten their friend. (10 minutes)

Act One: If I Only Had My Brain
Sarah Polley has always been reluctant to jump into challenging situations. Then something happened that changed all of that – something that also made her think her teeth were going to fall out. (21 minutes)

Act Two: Am I Doing It Alt-Right, You Guys?
Comedian Josh Johnson tells the story of a “trad wife” who stepped into an incendiary situation. And even as the flames consumed her, she kept stepping. (7 minutes)

Act Three: Mom Thinks He Doth Protest Too Much
This summer, thousands of young people have taken to the streets in Nairobi to protest the Kenyan government. But behind those protestors are thousands of worried parents. Reporter Kimu Elolia talks to a woman whose son keeps lying to her. (19 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/837.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>836: The Big Rethink (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/836/the-big-rethink</link>
      <itunes:episode>836</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>People rethinking some of the most important relationships in their lives.

Prologue
Ira observes that we are in a moment of national reconsideration. (2 minutes)

Act One: Fate of the Union
Zoe Chace reports on a surprising guest at the Republican National Convention: Teamsters president Sean O’Brien. (18 minutes)

Act Two: Out on a Limb
Ira talks to Representative Seth Moulton about what it was like to be among the first members of Congress to call for President Joe Biden to step aside. (18 minutes)

Act Three: Anything You Can Do I Can Do Backwards
Two adult sisters revisit old rivalries when they compete for a world record in typing with their pinkies. (16 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/836.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>835: Children of Dave (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/835/children-of-dave</link>
      <itunes:episode>835</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Boen Wang goes back to a day that changed the course of his family's story.

Prologue
Ira talks about what it’s like to go back to 1119 Bayard Street in Baltimore. (6 minutes)

Part One: Part One
Boen visits Norman, Oklahoma, where he was born, to meet the man he thinks changed his parents’ lives—and his life, too. (31 minutes)

Part Two: Part Two
Boen’s friend, Andrew, and his parents take what he learned in Part One, throw it into a blender, and push puree. (20 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/835.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>834: Yousef and the Fourth Move</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/834/yousef-and-the-fourth-move</link>
      <itunes:episode>834</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>In Rafah, Yousef is out of options and faces his toughest move yet.

Prologue
Since the beginning of the war in Gaza, Yousef Hammash has decided where to go next and when. In Rafah, he is out of options and faces his toughest move yet. (5 minutes)

Act One: Act One
Yousef does not even want to think about leaving Gaza. (18 minutes)

Act Two: Act Two
The actual price — in cash — of getting out of Gaza. (31 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/834/UsdYTu4b9F3SzU5sACfBFwR9RiJhvtDwW0tLUtkRvCA/834.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>833: Come Retribution (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/833/come-retribution</link>
      <itunes:episode>833</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Trump has a plan for his second term: retribution. We check in with the people who’ve crossed him.

Prologue
Donald Trump has talked about taking revenge on his enemies since the early days of his 2024 presidential campaign. Ira Glass talks to reporter Jonathan Karl about how Trump has placed retribution at the center of his run and what we know about how he’s thinking about it. (16 minutes)

Act One: Republicans Who Crossed Trump
Reporter Alix Spiegel talks to two people with good reason to fear a second Trump administration. Former White House Press Secretary Stephanie Grisham spent six years with the Trumps but resigned after January 6th and wrote a scathing tell-all book about her experience. Fred Wellman worked for The Lincoln Project - a group of high-profile Republicans who pledged to keep Trump out of office during the 2020 campaign. (22 minutes)

Act Two: The Deep Stater
Alex Vindman became the face of the first Trump impeachment after he reported to his superiors that Trump had asked the President of Ukraine to investigate Hunter Biden, the son of his political opponent. At the time, Vindman believed that his Congressional testimony would not jeopardize him; now, he and his wife Rachel are having second thoughts. (14 minutes)

Act Three: Four More Years
After hearing from people who dread a possible second Trump term, we hear from those who are excited about it. Reporter Zoe Chace checks into whether his supporters are excited for retribution. (7 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/833.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>832: That Other Guy (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/832/that-other-guy</link>
      <itunes:episode>832</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>People tethered to one particular other person, whether they want to be or not.

Prologue
Guest host Emmanuel Dzotsi talks to Leroy Smith about how one high school basketball tryout forever changed Leroy’s relationship to a childhood friend. (7 minutes)

Act One: I Would Run 500 Miles
A man finds himself sucked into an intense head-to-head running competition against a perfect rival – all for free burritos from Chipotle. (18 minutes)

Act Two: I Wish I Knew How to Force Quit You
Writer Simon Rich grapples with an A.I. chatbot that threatens to make him obsolete. (21 minutes)

Act Three: You, Me and Her
For writer Marie Phillips, moving in with her partner meant finding herself deeply connected to the woman who came before her. (12 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/832.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>831: Lists!!! (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/831/lists</link>
      <itunes:episode>831</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>How they organize the chaos of the world, for good and for bad.

Prologue
Ira interviews David Wallechinsky, who wrote a wildly popular book in the 1970s called The Book of Lists, full of trivia and research, gathered into lists like "18 Brains" and "What They Weighed." The book sold millions of copies and had four sequels and a brief spin-off TV show. The list books were like the internet, before the internet. (12 minutes)

Act One: List for Life
John Fecile talks to his brother, Pat, about a list their other brother made before he died. They each have different ideas about what the list means and how they feel about it. (14 minutes)

Throw Me a Bone Here
A brief visit with Bobby, who keeps a list in his phone of all the dogs in his neighborhood and their names to save him from the awkwardness of not knowing the name of someone’s dog – because people get upset if you don’t remember their dog’s name. (3 minutes)

Act Two: Target List
Reporter M. Gessen talks to Russians living in America and elsewhere about the lists the Russian government has put them on in the last few years. M. Gessen is also on one of these lists. Each list has its own complex rules and potential consequences for the people on the lists and for their family members who live in Russia. (28 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/831.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>830: The Forever Trial (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/830/the-forever-trial</link>
      <itunes:episode>830</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>The trial for the men accused of orchestrating the September 11 terrorist attacks still hasn’t started yet.

Prologue
Host Ira Glass introduces the new series that Serial is doing about Guantánamo Bay. This is the second of two episodes of theirs that we’re airing. (2 minutes)

Act One: Act One
We meet Colleen Kelly, a member of September 11th Families for Peaceful Tomorrows, and learn just how upside down and messed up the trial for the 9/11 accused has been over the past decade. (28 minutes)

Act Two: Act Two
Sarah Koenig explains what’s probably the best possible outcome that everyone can hope for at this point. And why, when it hits the news someday — if it ever happens — it’s sure to be deeply misunderstood by lots of people. Plus a trip to Guantánamo with Colleen. (31 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/830.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>829: Two Ledgers (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/829/two-ledgers</link>
      <itunes:episode>829</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Majid believed that if he could testify in court about what happened to him at a CIA black site, he would be given a break. Was he right?

Prologue
Ira talks about the exciting new series that Serial is doing about Guantánamo Bay. We’re airing two of those episodes on the show – one this week and one next. (2 minutes)

Act One: Act One
Majid Khan struggled with his identity when he was young. And then he realized exactly who he wanted to be – a member of Al Qaeda, carrying out orders for Khalid Sheikh Mohammed. He did bad things. But are the things that the U.S. Government did to him worse than his actual crimes?  (38 minutes)

Act Two: Act Two
Majid finally gets his day in court. At his sentencing hearing, he describes to the jury what his interrogators did to him. (20 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/829.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>828: Minor Crimes Division (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/828/minor-crimes-division</link>
      <itunes:episode>828</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>People taking it upon themselves to solve the tiny, overlooked crimes of the world.

Prologue
Host Ira Glass bikes around Manhattan with Gersh Kuntzman, in search of illegal license plates. (11 minutes)

Act One: Harriot Vs Harriot
Writer Michael Harriot reexamines the DIY criminal justice system his mom invented to deal with his bad behavior as a child. (20 minutes)

Act Two: Alternate Side
Producer Aviva DeKornfeld talks to Caveh Zahedi about a crime he may or may not have committed, depending on who you ask. (7 minutes)

Act Three: Jewel Intentions
Micaela Blei accidentally solves a crime that had been going on for a long time, right under her nose, and has to decide what to do next. She told this story onstage at The Moth. (7 minutes)

Act Four: Occam’s Toilet
Editor Bethel Habte examines video evidence of two parents trying to get to the bottom of a minor crime committed in their own home. (7 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/828.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>827: All the King's Horses (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/827/all-the-kings-horses</link>
      <itunes:episode>827</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>The things we break and the ones we can't fix.

Prologue
Ira tells the stories of three things that broke–two of them in his own family. (8 minutes)

Act One: Toy R Us
A teenage whiz kid invents a new toy for Milton Bradley. Then the trouble starts. (28 minutes)

Act Two: The 95
Reporter Dana Ballout sifts through a very long list—the list of journalists killed in the Israel-Hamas War—and comes back with five small fragments of the lives of the people on it. (10 minutes)

Act Three: A Great Fall
A skateboarding legend makes a final attempt at a high-flying trick. (6 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/827.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>826: Unprepared for What Has Already Happened (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/826/unprepared-for-what-has-already-happened</link>
      <itunes:episode>826</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>People waking up to the fact that the world has suddenly changed.

Prologue
Jackson Landers tells the story of a very strange decision he made one summer day. (6 minutes)

Act One: It’s Probably Nothing
Elena Kostyuchenko tells the story of how she was probably poisoned after reporting on Russian’s invasion of Ukraine, and how she kept not believing it was happening. Bela Shayevich translated this story from Russian and reads it for us. (21 minutes)

Act Two: We At The Hotel, Motel, Very Locked In
A recording of comedian Tig Notaro in the process of trying to catch up to the present and absolutely not being able to. (8 minutes)

Act Three: That’s My Story and I’m Absolutely Not Sticking to It
Producer Zoe Chace with a political fable that she noticed playing out last week in North Carolina. (11 minutes)

Act Four: What’d I Miss?
Producer Tobin Low finds a group of people with a special relationship with the idea of catching up. (10 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/826.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>825: Yousef’s Week</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/825/yousef</link>
      <itunes:episode>825</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>A series of phone calls to a man in Gaza about what he and his family are experiencing.

Act One: Act One
Over the course of one week in December, Yousef tries to get his sisters to safety, in Rafah. (29 minutes)

Act Two: Act Two
Yousef is managing a camp of 60 people in Rafah, including his youngest sister, who is 8 months pregnant. Every day there’s talk that Israel will launch a ground assault in Rafah. Yousef and his sister make a plan for her to give birth safely, but it doesn’t go according to plan. And all 60 people in the family are looking to Yousef to tell them where they should go next and how to stay safe. (27 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/825/b7TFyE3Z52phRm3UICpZS4goMGV9NDRIqEYLOrGx_9Y/825.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>824: Family Meeting (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/824/family-meeting</link>
      <itunes:episode>824</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>Your mother and I have something we want to talk with you about.

Prologue
A family sits down to discuss one thing. But then the true purpose of the meeting emerges. (9 ½ minutes)

Act One: A Slow Decision Process That’s Mostly But Maybe Not Completely Over
For one kibbutz-dwelling family in Israel, the decision of where to land after the October 7th attacks goes back and forth… and back… and forth. (28 minutes)


Ira learns about — and has a few thoughts on — one coach’s striking technique to keep the morale of his high school football team on the up, week after week. (3 ½ minutes)

Act Two: Sealed With A Diss
An excerpt from “Belles Lettres," a short story by Nafissa Thompson-Spires from her book Heads of the Colored People, performed by actors Erika Alexander and Eisa Davis with a cameo from our colleague Alvin Melathe. (14 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/824.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>823: The Question Trap (Clean)</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/823/the-question-trap</link>
      <itunes:episode>823</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
      <description>An investigation of when and why people ask loaded questions that are a proxy for something else.

Prologue
Host Ira Glass talks with producer Tobin Low about the question he got asked after he and his husband moved in together, and what he thinks people were really asking. (4 minutes)

Act One: Question: Tell Me What You Think About This
“What do you think about Beyoncé?” and other questions raised by people on first dates. (12 minutes)

Act Two: How Old Are Your Kids?
When a common, seemingly innocuous question goes wildly off the rails. (13 minutes)

Act Three: How’s Your Mom?
Why are people asking me if my mother recognizes me, when it’s totally beside the point? (14 minutes)

Act Four: Can I Help You?
Schools ask their students the strangest essay questions sometimes. The experience of tutoring anxious teenagers through how to answer them requires a balladier, singing their lived experience to a crowd as though it were the Middle Ages. (10 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/upload/clean/823.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>822: The Words to Say It</title>
      <link>https://www.thisamericanlife.org/822/the-words-to-say-it</link>
      <itunes:episode>822</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:explicit>yes</itunes:explicit>
      <description>What it means to have words—and to lose them.

Prologue
Sometimes we don’t want to say what’s going on because putting it into words would make it real. At other times, words don’t seem to capture the weight of what we want to say. Susanna Fogel talks about her friend Margaret Riley, who died earlier this week. (6 minutes)

Act One: The Speaking Part
The story of a woman from Gaza City who ran out of words. Seventy-two days into the war, Youmna stopped talking. (27 minutes)

Act Two: Toska
For years there was a word that Val’s mother did not want to use. Val sets out to figure out why. (22 minutes)</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://www.thisamericanlife.org/sites/default/files/audio/822/KK8hozWKStRe5YYF712MN-7lO_lt7t_c3WZLoOHplgY/822.mp3" type="audio/mpeg"/>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
